Charlie Tung

New York, NY | 917-328-6763 | choelestung@gmail.com Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Software Engineer

Full stack web developer with a passion for learning. With experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Nodejs, React and Redux, and a background in business administration, I discovered web development through my path into fintech. I have a passion for solving puzzles, optimization, and intuitive design which helps increase productivity and efficiency. There are many ways to solve the same problem but how efficient and effective your solution is, is as important as how fast you can get a solution to work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript Node Express React Redux Ruby Rails Git PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB Sass HTML CSS ORM ODM Liquid

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Prospect Farms - Website

E-Commerce site for CBD products

- Developed using javascript and liquid templating language to create a custom, modular filter component for all the product pages to filter out by variants, size, use and flavor
- Implemented and developed 2 templates to organize and format the collection of products using javascript
- Combined and customize instafeed is plugin and flickity is to make modular social media carousel component

Stocky - Github | Demo

Stock Tracker Application that shows price changes in a minimalistic form

- Built a detailed visualization of stock data in multiple time frames to provide accurate data representation
- Implemented a search engine with react-select allowing for quick selection and searching of different companies
- Created RESTful APIs to store persistent data for user portfolio and for application loading optimization

Flatiron Life - Github | Demo | Video

Video game inspired by The Legend of Zelda

- Built a fun and interactive game around the daily life and struggles of a Flatiron Student mastering app development
- Implemented a physics engine with JavaScript to model similar game design as the Legend of Zelda Game
- Rendered game sprites for character and level design; played custom game audio for interactions and music
- Created RESTful APIs to store persistent data for multiple players

EXPERIENCE

Freelance 04/2020 - Present

- Collaboration with other freelancers and designers on applications
- Creates 2-3 features every 2 weeks

Associates in Business Administration

Maintains and optimizes codebase to have modular design

Course Assistant, 2U/Trilogy Ed, New York, NY

09/2019 - 04/2020

- Teach transitioning professionals how to become web developers to start their new careers
- Maintain an average of 8/10 score on weekly feedback assessing students' understanding of the material
- Actively incorporates biweekly feedback with staff to create customized learning experience for each student

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Immersive program	06/2018 - 08/2018
Baruch College, New York, NY Coursework towards Bachelors in Computer Information Systems Completed courses included: Object Oriented Programming	01/2018 - 05/2018
LaGuardia Community College, New York, NY	02/2017 - 12/2017